Register of the Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman collection, 1899-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
- Boris Pasternak File, 1910-1998.
  - Printed matter. Publications by and about Boris Pasternak, arranged chronologically. Boris Pasternak's name is omitted when he is the author. Hardback, unless otherwise indicated (Box 27)
    - General
      - Iakubovich, V., Darstvennye nadpisi na knigakh iz chastnykh sobranii, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Litsa: Biograficheskii al'manakh, Atheneum-Feniks, Moscow-St. Petersburg, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Pis'ma B. L. Pasternaka k zhene Z. N. Neigauz, K. M. Polivanov, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Schweitzer, Viktoria, Tsvetaeva, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Turning the Page, Christopher MacLehose, ed., 1993 (Box 42)
      - Val's s chertovshchinoi, A. M. Galkina, ed., 1993 (Box 42)
      - Vospominaniia o Borise Pasternake, E. V. Pasternak and M. I. Feinberg, eds., 1993 (Box 42)
      - Moskva, October-November 1993 (Box 42)
      - Minuvshee: Istoricheskii al'manakh, Atheneum-Feniks, Moscow-St. Petersburg, 1993-1994 (Box 42)
      - Boris Pasternak, Vsemirnaia Biblioteka Poezii, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Burton, Humphrey, Leonard Bernstein, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Kozovoi, Vadim, Poet v katastrofe, Izdatel'stvo "Gnosis,", 1994 (Box 43)
      - A Literary Book of Days, Crown Publishers, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Markov, Vladimir, Svoboda v Poezii, Izdatel'stvo Chernysheva, St. Petersburg, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Minuvshee: Istoricheskii al'manakh, Atheneum-Feniks, Moscow-St. Petersburg, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Pasternak, Anna, Princess in Love, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Raine, Craig, History: The Home Movie, 1994. (Box 43)
      - Reeder, Roberta, Anna Akhmatova, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Rudova, Larissa, Pasternak's Short Fiction and the Cultural Vanguard, Peter Lang, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Themes and Variations in Honor of Lazar Fleishman, Polivanov et al., eds., Stanford Slavic Studies, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Wurzburger, Walter, Ethics of Responsibility, The Jewish Publication Society, 1994 (Box 43)
      - Boris Pasternaks Lehrjahre, vol. II, Lazar Fleishman et al., Stanford Slavic Studies, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Clowes, Edith, Doctor Zhivago: A Critical Companion, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Ensign, Georgianne, Great Endings, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Etkind, Tam, vnutri: O russkoi poezii XX veka, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Festschrift für Hans-Bernd Harder, München, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Legendarnaia Ordynka, Mikhail Ardov et al., 1995 (Box 43)
      - Maslenikova, Zoia, Portret Borisa Pasternaka, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Russkie pisateli poety: Bibliograficheskii ukazatel', no. 18, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Sicher, Efraim, Jews in Russian Literature After the October Revolution, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Uslyshat' budushchego zov, Shkola-Press, Moscow, 1995 (Box 43)
      - The Writer's Drawing Book: The Russians, Redstone Editions, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Zholkovskii, Aleksandr, Inventsii, 1995 (Box 43)
      - Rashkovskaia, M. A., Boris Pasternak i Sergei Bobrov: Pis'ma chetyrekh desiatiletii, Stanford Slavic Studies, vol. 10, Stanford Slavic Studies, 1995-1996 (Box 43)
      - Boris Pasternaks Lehrjahre, vol. II, Lazar Fleishman et al., Stanford Slavic Studies, 1996 (Box 44)
      - Danin, Daniil, Bremia styda, 1996 (Box 44)
      - Gifford, Henry, Pasternak, 1996 (Box 44)
      - Nagibin, Iurii, Dnevnik, 1996 (Box 44)
      - Ozerov, Lev, Dver' v masterskuiu, 1996 (Box 44)
      - Sinyavsky, Andrei, Russian Intelligentsiia, Literaturnoe obozrenie, no. 4, 1996-1997 (Box 44)
      - Pis'ma k roditeliam i sestram, vol. 1, E. B. and E. V. Pasternak, eds., Stanford Slavic Studies, 1998 (Box 44)
      - Voprosy istorii, 1998 July (Box 44)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, Poetry and Revolution: Boris Pasternak's My Sister Life, Stanford Slavic Studies, 1999 (Box 44)
      - Mandel'shtam, Nadezhda, Hope Against Hope, Modern Library, 1999 (Box 44)
    - Doktor Zhivago, various translations and editions., See also Biographical file, Audio-visual file, and Oversize file (Box 45)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Feltrinelli Editore, Milan, 1957. (Box 45)
        Hardback
      - Il Dottore Zivago, Feltrinelli Editore, Milan (Box 45)
        - Uncorrected proof?, 1957 (Box 45)
        - Hardback, 1957; 1958 (Box 45)
      - Le Docteur Jivago, Librairie Gallimard, 1958 (Box 45)
      - Doctor Zhivago, Max Hayward and Manya Harari, translators, 1958 (Box 45)
        - Collins Fontana Books. (Box 45)
        - Collins and Harvill Press. (Box 45)
          Inscribed by translators. Hardback
        - Modern Library. (Box 45)
        - Pantheon Books. (Box 45)
        - Signet Book, New American Library. (Box 45)
        - Wm. Collins Sons and Co. Ltd. (Box 45)
          Uncorrected proof and paperback
      - Dokter Zjivago, A. W. Bruna & Zoon, Utrecht, 1958 (Box 45)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Ann Arbor, The University of Michigan Press, 1958 (Box 45)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Feltrinelli – Milan, 1958. (Box 45)
        Pirated first edition in Russian
      - Doktor Zhivago, Feltrinelli Editore, 1959? (Box 46)
      - Le Docteur Jivago, Librairie Gallimard, 1959. (Box 46)
      - Doctor Zhivago, Max Hayward and Manya Harari, translators, 1959 (Box 46)
        - Pantheon. Hardback (Box 46)
        - Signet Book, New American Library, 1959. (Box 46)
      - Dokter Zjivago, A. W. Bruna & Zoon, Utrecht, 1959 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, vols. 1-2, Société d'Édition d'Impression Mondiale, 1959 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zivago, Institut Literacki, Paryz, 1959 (Box 46)
      - Doctor Zhivago, Max Hayward and Manya Harari, trans., Fontana Monarchs, 1961, and Signet Book, New American Library (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Zemlia i Fabrika, 1964 (Box 46)
      - Il Dottore Zivago, Einaudi Editore, 1964 (Box 46)
      - David Lean's Film of Doctor Zhivago, 1965. (Box 46)
        Brochure
      - Il Dottore Zivago, Feltrinelli Editore, Milan, 1965 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Ann Arbor, The University of Michigan Press, 1967 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Am Oved Ltd., Tel Aviv, 1969. (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Feltrinelli Editore, Milan, 1978 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, The Franklin Library, 1978 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Ballantine Books, 1981 and 1986 (Box 46)
      - Il dottor Zivago, Romanzo Feltrinelli, 1982 (Box 46)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Easton Press, 1986 (Box 46)
      - Il Dottor Zivago, Feltrinelli, 1987 (Box 46)
      - Doctor Zhivago, Max Hayward and Manya Harari trans., 1988 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zhivago, vols. 1-2, Vil'nius VAGA, 1988 (Box 47)
      - Zsivago Doktor, Europa Konyvkiado, Budapest, 1988 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zhivago (Box 47)
        - Knizhnaia Palata, 1989-1990 (Box 47)
        - Sovetskii Pisatel', 1989 (Box 47)
      - Doctor Zhivago, The World's Best Reading, The Reader's Digest Association Inc., 1990 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zivago, Lidove Nakladatelstvi Edice Proudy, Prague, 1990 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zivago, Prague, 1990 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zywago, Panstwowy Institut Wydawniczy, Warsaw, 1990 (Box 47)
      - Doctor Zhivago, Max Hayward and Manya Harari, trans., Pantheon Books, Everyman's Library, and The Harvill Press London, 1991 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Tsenturion, 1991 (Box 47)
      - Doktor Zhivago, Izdatel'stvo Troika, Moscow, 1994 (Box 47)
      - Il Dottor Zivago, Universale Economica Feltrinelli, 1994 (Box 47)
      - Doctor Zhivago, Max Hayward and Manya Harari, trans. (Box 47)
        - Harper Collins, 1995. (Box 47)
        - Harvill Press, 1996. (Box 47)
        - Folio Society, 1997. (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous printed matter related to Russia and the Soviet Union (Box 48)
      - Popular journals (Box 48)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 48)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 48)
- Boris Pasternak 2001 Increment File, 1958-2000. (Box 48)
  One print, depicting the death mask of Boris Pasternak, and printed matter, arranged chronologically by title
  - Photograph, n.d. (Box 51)
    One print depicting the death mask of Boris Pasternak
  - Printed matter. Publications about or by Boris Pasternak, 1958-2001.
    Pasternak's name is omitted where he is the author
    - Doktor Zhivago, in two volumes, Tel Aviv, 1958. (Box 51)
    - Essai d'autobiographie, Paris, 1958. (Box 51)
      French translation of Boris Pasternak's memoirs
    - Mivar Shirim, Tel Aviv, 1958(?). (Box 51)
      Hebrew translation of Stikhi
    - Abel, Lionel, "On Doctor Zhivago," Dissent, 1958 Autumn. (Box 51)
      Printed copy of whole issue
    - Doktor Zshivago, in two volumes, Tel Aviv, 1959. (Box 51)
      In Yiddish
    - New World Writing, no. 15, 1959. (Box 51)
      Includes English translation of "Il Tratto di Apelle"
    - Les voies aériennes et autres nouvelles, Paris, 1966. (Box 51)
      French translation of short stories
    - Doctor Zhivago, abridged and simplified, London, 1978 (Box 51)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, Personal Impressions, New York, 1980. (Box 51)
      Includes chapter, "Meetings with Russian Writers 1945 and 1956"
    - Gass, Boris, Zadui vo Mne Svechu, London, 1984 (Box 52)
    - Kazin, Alfred, A Lifetime Burning in Every Moment, New York, 1996 (Box 52)
    - Barnes, Christopher, Boris Pasternak: A Literary Biography, volume two, London, 1998 (Box 52)
    - Gordin, Iakov, Pereklichka vo Mrake, St. Petersburg, 2000. (Box 52)
      Also includes material on Joseph Brodsky
    - Letters: Summer 1926, New York, 2001. (Box 52)
      English translation of correspondence among Boris Pasternak, Marina Tsvetayeva, and Rainer Maria Rilke
- Boris Pasternak 2004 Increment File, 1923-2003.
  Livonov collection of books, drawings, letters, and other printed matter, arranged by physical form and chronologically by title thereunder, and printed matter, sound recordings, and art work, arranged by physical form and chronologically by title thereunder. Materials received in 2004
  - Livanov collection
    - Books written or translated by Pasternak and inscribed to Boris and Evgeniia Livanov, 1923-1949
      - Sestra moia zhizn' Berlin/Petersburg/Moscow, 1923 (Box-folder 149: 1)
      - Dve knigi, Moscow/Leningrad, 1927. (Folder 149: 2)
        Flyleaf contains holograph variant of Pasternak poem, "Bit' znemenitym nekrasivo"
      - Gamlet, Moscow, 1941 (Folder 149: 3)
      - Antonii i Kleopatra, Moscow, 1944 (Folder 149: 4)
      - Romeo i Dzhul'etta, Moscow, 1944 (Folder 149: 5)
      - Izbrannye stikhi i poemy, Moscow, 1945 (Folder 149: 6)
      - Zemnoi prostor, Moscow, 1945 (Folder 149: 7)
      - Vil'iam Shekspir v perevode Borisa Pasternaka, vol. 2, Moscow/Leningrad, 1949 (Box-folder 150: 1)
    - Letters from Pasternak to Boris and Evgeniia Livanov
      - Envelope addressed to Boris Livanov, 1941. (Folder 150: 2)
        Includes piece of paper with Pasternak signature, n.d.
      - Letter to Boris Livanov, 1944 March 8 (Folder 150: 3)
      - Letter to Evgeniia Livanov, 1950 November 8. (Folder 150: 4)
        Includes typescript of unpublished book of Pasternak's poetry
    - Other printed matter, 2002-2003
      - Livanov, Vasilii, Nevydumannyi Boris Pasternak, Moscow, 2002 (Folder 150: 5)
      - Mir Inkom Daidzhest, no. 1, 2003. (Folder 150: 6)
        Contains an interview with Vasilii Livanov
    - Drawings by Boris Livanov, 1944-1956
      - Two encapsulated sketches depicting Boris Pasternak, n.d. (Folder 150: 7)
      - One encapsulated sketch depicting Zinaida Pasternak, n.d. (Folder 150: 8)
      - One framed sketch depicting Boris Pasternak, n.d. (Folder 150: 9)
      - One framed sketch depicting Boris Pasternak, 1944 (Box-folder 164: 1)
      - One framed sketch depicting Boris Pasternak, 1956 (Folder 164: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1924-2003. (Box 151)
    Publications by or about Pasternak, including works translated by Pasternak. Pasternak's name is omitted where he is the author or translator. Printed copies unless otherwise noted
    - Russkaia lirika, Paris, 1924 (Folder 151: 1)
    - Vozdushnye puti, Moscow, 1933 (Folder 151: 2)
    - Childhood, Singapore, 1941. (Folder 151: 3)
    - "Zametki perevodchika," Znamia, nos. 1-2, 1944 (Folder 151: 4)
    - "The Death of Mayakovsky," Accent, 1946 Autumn (Folder 151: 5)
    - Vil'iam Shekspir v perevode Borisa Pasternaka, volume 2, Moscow/Leningrad, 1949 (Folder 151: 6)
    - Doctor Zhivago, London, 1958. (Box-folder 152: 1)
      Annotated by James Stern. Includes two letters addressed to James Stern from John Lehmann and Charles Osborne, 1958-1959
    - "Translating Shakespeare," The Twentieth Century, 1958 September (Folder 152: 2)
    - Lowell, Robert, Imitations, New York, 1961 (Folder 152: 3)
    - Bolt, Robert, shooting script for the movie "Doctor Zhivago,", 1964 (Folder 152: 4)
    - Troitsky, N. A., Boris Leonidovich Pasternak, 1890-1960: Bibliografiia proizvedenii B. Pasternaka i literatury o nem na russkom iazyke, Ithaca, New York, 1969 (Folder 152: 5)
    - Durant, Will and Ariel, Interpretations of Life: A Survey of Contemporary Literature, New York, 1970 (Box-folder 153: 1)
    - Program for a performance by Robert Bolt, 1972 June 18 (Folder 153: 2)
    - Krotkov, Yuri, The Nobel Prize, London, 1980 (Folder 153: 3)
    - Efron, Ariadna and Boris Pasternak, Pis'ma iz ssylki, Paris, 1982 (Folder 153: 4)
    - "2-aia kartina. Peterburg," Novyi Mir, no. 5, 1990 (Folder 153: 5)
    - Literaturnoe obozrenie, no. 2., 1990. (Folder 153: 6)
      Issue devoted to Pasternak
    - Stikhotvoreniia I poemy. Perevody, Moscow, 1990 (Box-folder 154: 1)
    - Doctor Zhivago, London, 1991 (Folder 154: 2)
    - Lieutenant Schmidt, London, 1992 (Folder 154: 3)
    - Danin, Daniil, Bremia styda, Moscow, 1996 (Folder 154: 4)
    - The Life of Boris Pasternak's Doctor Zhivago: The First 50 Years, exhibit program, Moscow, 1998 December 7-8 (Folder 154: 5)
    - Doctor Zhivago, London, 2002 (Box 155)
      - Second printing (Folder 155: 1)
      - Third printing (Folder 155: 2)
    - Feltrinelli, Carlo, Feltrinelli, 2002 (Folder 155: 3)
    - Livanov, Vasilii, Nevydumannyi Boris Pasternak, Moscow, 2002 (Folder 155: 4)
    - Biondi, Lee, "Boris Pasternak's Doctor Zhivago," Firsts, 2003 June (Folder 155: 5)
  - Sound recordings, 1994-1998 (Box 156)
    - Doctor Zhivago, read by Bob Peck, 1994. (Folder 156: 1-2)
      Two compact sound cassettes
    - Doctor Zhivagoc, read by Philip Madoc, 1995. (Folder 156: 3-10)
      Eight compact sound cassettes
    - Boris Leonidovich Pasternak: Poeziia, read by Viktor Zozulin, 1998. (Folder 156: 11)
      One compact sound cassette
  - Art work, n.d. (Box 164)
    - Framed caricature of Pasternak by David Levine, n.d. (Folder 164: 3)
- Leonid Pasternak File, 1915-1988.
  Brochures from exhibits of Leonid Pasternak's work; publications by and about Leonid Pasternak, arranged chronologically by title or author, with the spellings conforming to those of the original publications. Transliterations are supplied for non-Roman alphabets
  - Brochures from exhibits of Leonid Pasternak's work, 1988 (Box 49)
  - Publications by and about Leonid Pasternak. (Box 49)
    Includes books illustrated by him
    - Tolstoy, Lev, Resurrection, Foreign Languages Publishing House, Moscow, n.d. (Box 49)
      Illustrated by Leonid Pasternak
    - Den' pechati "Klich": Sbornik na pomoshch zhertvam voiny, Moscow, 1915 (Box 49)
    - Unidentified book in Hebrew, Jibneh-Jerusalem Kunst und Buchverlag, 1920's (Box 49)
    - Zapisi raznykh let, Sovetskii khudozhnik, 1975 (Box 49)
    - The Memoirs of Leonid Pasternak, Jennifer Bradshaw, trans., 1982 (Box 49)
    - A Russian Impressionist: Paintings and Drawings by Leonid Pasternak, 1890-1945, Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service, 1987 (Box 49)
  - Oversize file (Box 50)
    - Shtruk, German, Akademik L. O. Pasternak: Al'bom Portretov, Jibneh-Verlag, Jerusalem-Berlin, 1923 (Box 50)
    - Bialik, C. and Mar Osborn, Leonid Pasternak: His Life and Work, Stybel Publishing House, Warsaw, 1924. (Box 50)
      In Russian, Hebrew and English
- Leonid Pasternak 2004 Increment File, 1900.
  Monograph received in 2004
  - Printed copy of Tolstoy, Leo, Voskresenie, Purleigh, England, 1900. (Box-folder 157: 1)
    Illustrations by Leonid Pasternak
- Isaac Babel File, 1913-2002.
  Art works, articles, audiotapes, catalog, certificate, compact disc, correspondence, monographs, photographs, poems, serials issues, and videotapes, arranged according to criteria established by the collector: collection catalog; works; anthologies; criticism; reference; life; memoirs; art; audio, video, film; photography; collections, exhibitions, conferences. There is also a heading for oversize and miscellaneous materials, boxes 147-148. Original catalog numbers appear in parentheses. For the most part, Babel's name is omitted where he is the author. Transliterations are supplied for non-Roman alphabets
  - Collection catalog, n.d. (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Works, 1913-2002.
    Printed copies, unless otherwise indicated. Two items (I.45, I.46) are to be found in Oversize and miscellaneous materials, box 147
    - "Stary Shloime," Ogni, no. 6., 1913 February 9 (Folder 55: 2)
      (I.1)
    - "Mama, Rimma i Alla," Leptopis', 1916 November (Folder 55: 3)
      (I.2)
    - "Kvaker," Lava, no. 1, 1920 (Folder 55: 4)
      (I.3)
    - "Moi pervyi gus'," Lef, 1924 (Folder 55: 5)
      no. 1 (I.4)
    - "Konarmiia" and "Odesskie rasskazy," Lef, 1924 (Folder 55: 6)
      no. 4 (I.5)
    - "Pervaia liubov'," Al'manakh Krasnaia Nov', 1925 (Folder 55: 7)
      no. 1 (I.6)
    - Rasskazy, Moscow, 1925 (Folder 55: 8-9)
      (I.7, I.8)
    - Liubka kozak, Moscow, 1925 (Folder 55: 10)
      (I.9)
    - Istoriia moei golubiatni, Moscow-Leningrad, 1926 (Folder 55 :11-12)
      (I.10, I.10A)
    - Istoriia moei golubiatni, Moscow-Leningrad, 1978 (Box-folder 56 :1-2)
      (I.10B, I.10C)
    - Sovetskii Ekran, no. 7., 1926 February 16 (Folder 56: 3)
    - Bluzhdaiushchie zvezdy, Moscow, 1926 (Folder 56: 4)
      (I.11A)
    - Bluzhdaiushchie zvezdy, Ann Arbor, 1972 (Folder 56: 5-6)
      (I.11B, I.11C)
    - Bluzhdaiushchie zvezdy, Ann Arbor, 1980 (Folder 56: 7)
      (I.11D)
    - Photograph of 1927 poster advertising film of Bluzhdaiushchie zvezdy, n.d. (Folder 56: 8)
      (I.11E). One print
    - Konarmia, Moscow-Leningrad, 1928 (Folder 56: 9)
      (I.12)
    - Benia Krik, Moscow-Leningrad, 1926 (Folder 56: 10)
      (I.13)
    - Geschichten aus Odessa, Berlin, 1926 (Folder 56: 11)
      (I.14). German translation of Odesskie rasskazy
    - Bereshit, Tel Aviv, 1927. (Folder 56: 12)
      Includes Hebrew translation of six stories by Babel
    - Konets sv. Ipatiia, Moscow-Leningrad, 1927 (Folder 56: 13)
      (I.16)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow-Leningrad, 1927 (Box-folder 57: 1)
      (I.17)
    - Rasskazy, Moscow-Leningrad, 1927 (Folder 57: 2)
      (I.18)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow, 1927 (Folder 57: 3)
      (I.19)
    - Di geshikhte fun mayn toybnshlak, Vilnius, 1927 (Folder 57: 4)
      (I.20). Yiddish translation of Istoriia moei golubiatni
    - Zakat, Moscow(?), 1928 (Folder 57: 5)
      (I.21)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow-Leningrad, 1928 (Folder 57: 6-7)
      (I.22, I.23)
    - Konarmiia, London (Folder 57: 8)
      (I.23A)
    - Red Cavalry, New York and London, 1929 (Folder 57: 9)
      (I.24). English translation of Konarmiia
    - Konarmiia, Moscow-Leningrad, 1930 (Box-folder 58: 1)
      (I.25)
    - Los jinetes de Budienny: La caballara roja, 1930. (Folder 58: 2)
      Spanish translation of Konarmiia
    - Konarmiia, Moscow-Leningrad, 1931 (Folder 58: 3)
      (I.27)
    - Odesskie rasskazy, Moscow-Leningrad, 1931 (Folder 58: 4)
      (I.28)
    - Rasskazy, Moscow, 1932 (Folder 58: 5)
      (I.29)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow, 1933 (Folder 58: 6)
      (I.30)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow, 1934 (Folder 58: 7-8)
      (I.31, I.31A)
    - Konarmiia, Moscow, 1934 (Box-folder 59: 1)
      (I.31B)
    - Rasskazy, Moscow, 1935 (Folder 59: 2)
      (I.32)
    - Mariia, Moscow, 1935 (Folder 59: 3)
      (I.33)
    - "Two Soviet Short Stories," International Literature, no. 3, 1935 (Folder 59: 4)
      (I.34)
    - "Oil," International Literature, no. 4, 1935 (Folder 59: 5)
      (I.35)
    - "It Happened in Odessa," International Literature, no. 6, 1935 (Folder 59: 6)
      (I.36)
    - "King of the Gangsters," International Literature, no. 9, 1935 (Folder 59: 7)
      (I.37)
    - Benia Krik, London, 1935 (Folder 59: 8)
      (I.38)
    - Benia Krik, Westport, Conn., 1973 (Folder 59: 9)
      (I.39)
    - Benia Krik, London, 1984 (Folder 59: 10)
      (I.40)
    - Izbrannye rasskazy, Moscow, 1936 (Folder 59: 11)
      (I.41)
    - Rasskazy, Moscow, 1936 (Folder 59: 12)
      (I.42)
    - "Bagritskii," in Narbut, Vladimir, ed., Eduard Bagritskii: Almanakh, Moscow, 1936. (Box-folder 60: 1)
      (I.43)
    - "In the Basement," Contemporary Poetry and Prose, no. 3, 1936 July (Folder 60: 2)
      (I.44)
    - Benya Krik the Gangster, New York, 1948 (Folder 60: 3-4)
      (I.48, I48A). English translation of Benia Krik
    - Benya Krik the Gangster, New York, 1969 (Folder 60: 5)
      (I.49)
    - Benya Krik the Gangster, London, 1971 (Folder 60: 6)
      (I.50)
    - "In the Cellar," Commentary, vol. 5, no. 1, 1948 January (Folder 60: 7)
      (I.51)
    - "The Sin of Jesus," Partisan Review, vol. 16, no. 1, 1949 January (Folder 60: 8)
      (I.52)
    - "Guy de Maupassant," Partisan Review, vol. 17, no. 1, 1950 January (Folder 60: 9)
      (I.53)
    - "V shchelochu," Opyty, no. 3, 1954 (Box-folder 61: 1)
      (I.54)
    - Collected Stories, New York, 1955 (Folder 61: 2)
      (I.55). English translation by Walter Morison of Konarmiia, Odesskie rasskazy, and Rasskazy
    - Collected Stories, London, 1957 (Folder 61: 3)
      (I.56). Reprint of Morison translation
    - Collected Stories, Harmondsworth, 1961 (Folder 61: 4)
      (I.57). Reprint of Morison translation
    - Izbrannoe, Moscow, 1957 (Box-folder 62: 1)
      (I.58)
    - "Sunset," Noonday, no. 3, 1960 (Folder 62: 2)
      (I.59). English translation of Zakat
    - Sunset, New York, n.d. (Folder 62: 3)
      (I.66)
    - "A Reply to an Inquiry," The Noble Savage, no. 3, 1961 (Folder 62: 3)
      (I.61)
    - "Regards to Odessa," Midstream, vol. 7, no. 4, 1961 Autumn (Folder 62: 4)
      (I.62)
    - Sipurim, Tel Aviv, 1963 (Folder 62: 5)
      (I.63, I.63A). Hebrew translation of Rasskazy
    - Lyubka the Cossack, 1963 (Box-folder 63: 1)
      (I.64)
    - "My First Fee," Encounter, vol. 23, no. 2, 1964 August (Folder 63: 2)
      (I.65)
    - Konarmiia, Odesskie rasskazy, P'ecy, Chicago, 1965 (Folder 63: 3)
    - L'armata a cavallo, Milan, 1965 (Folder 63: 4)
      (I.67). Italian translation of Konarmiia
    - Zabytye rasskazy, Letchworth, 1965 (Folder 63: 5)
      (I.68)
    - Chetyre rasskaza, Letchworth, 1965 (Folder 63: 6)
      (I.69)
    - Izbrannoe, Moscow, 1966 (Folder 63: 7)
      (I.70)
    - Izbrannoe, Kemerevo, 1966 (Box-folder 64: 1)
      (I.71)
    - "Maria," Tri-Quarterly, no. 5, 1966 (Folder 64: 2)
    - "Forgotten Stories," Stand, vol. 7, no. 2 (Folder 64: 3)
      (I.73)
    - "Marya," in Glenny, Michael, ed., Three Soviet Plays, Harmondsworth, 1966 (Folder 64: 4)
      (I.74)
    - "Two Stories," Commentary, vol. 45, no. 1, 1968 January (Folder 64: 5)
      (I.75)
    - Tsvena Konjitsa, Novi Sad, 1967 (Folder 64: 6)
      (I.76). Serbian translation of Konarmiia
    - Odesa Novi Sad, (I.76B). Serbian translation of Odesskie rasskazy (Box-folder 65: 1)
    - O vremenu i sebi, (I.76C). Serbian translation of selected correspondence (Folder 65: 2)
    - Collected Stories, Cleveland, 1969 (Folder 65: 3)
      (I.77)
    - You Must Know Everything, New York, 1969. (Folder 65: 4)
      English translation by Max Hayward of Rasskazy. First printing (I.78) and second printing (I.78A)
    - You Must Know Everything, London, 1970 (Box-folder 66: 1)
      (I.78B)
    - Tramanto, Milan, 1971 (Folder 66: 2)
      (I.79). Italian translation of Zakat
    - Utwory odnalezione, Warsaw, 1971 (Folder 66: 3)